#### Gilvan Ritter

Location

Porto Alegre, Brazil

**Email** 

gilvanritter@gmail.com

LinkedIn

linkedin.com/in/grittt

**GitHub** 

github.com/gritt

Website

gilv.es

#### Intro

Software Engineer with over 8 years of experience, currently working at Nubank.

Experienced in backend development, microservices, software architecture and agile culture, worked with a diverse set of technologies, teams of different cultures and sizes and projects with small and large scale.

## Experience

Senior Software Engineer at Nubank since January 2022 in Porto Alegre, Brazil.

**Senior Development Consultant** at ThoughtWorks from October 2020 to September 2021 in Porto Alegre, Brazil.

Continue watching microservice for major Brazilian streaming service, with data intensive design and up to 15k requests per second.

Golang, Redis Cache, Redis Streams, Cassandra, GitLabCl, Sentry, Prometheus, Grafana.

Microservices, Clean Architecture, Domain Driven Design, Cl and CD, Monitoring, Documentation, C4 Model, Unit Tests, Integration Tests, Load Tests, Tracing, Scalability, Data-Intensive, Site Reliability Engineering, Caching Strategies, Data Migration.

**Development Consultant** at ThoughtWorks from January 2019 to October 2020 in Porto Alegre, Brazil.

Resource authorization platform for major Brazilian streaming service.

Golang, ActiveMQ, MySQL, Sentry, NewRelic, GitLabCl, JS, TypeScript, React, React Hooks, HTML, CSS, Google Analytics SDK.

Clean Architecture, Clean Code, Cl and CD, Monitoring, Observability, Metrics, Documentation, Unit Tests, Integration Tests, End2End Tests, Snapshot Tests, Visual Regression Tests, Communication, Effective Feedback, Continuous Improvement, Negotiation, Lean Inception.

Distributed podcast platform for major Brazilian streaming service.

NodeJS, JS, Web Components, React, Storybook, MongoDB, HTML, CSS, GitLabCl.

Event Driven Architecture, Function as a Service (FaaS), CI and CD, Documentation, C4 Model, Unit Tests, Integration Tests, Snapshot Tests, Visual Regression Tests.

**Backend Developer** at StartStudio from April 2018 to December 2018 in Pelotas, Brazil.

Optimization and migration of multi tenant radio management and streaming service to cloud.

Refactoring, PHP7, CakePHP, Redis Cache, Nginx, MySQL, MySQL Replication, Docker, AWS SDK, DigitalOcean Containers and Spaces, Minio, Git, Linux, Server Management.

**Backend Developer** at POSSIBLE from August 2015 to March 2018 in Pelotas, Brazil.

Development of RESTFul APIs and CMSs with cloud integrations, from concept to production.

PHP7, Vagrant, Docker, Nginx, CakePHP, Symfony, MySQL, PowerPoint Document API, AWS SQS, Redis, AWS S3, AWS SES, Firebase Cloud Messaging, HTML5, CSS, Bootstrap.

Junior Backend Developer at W8S from July 2014 to June 2015 in Pelotas, Brazil.

Support and develop CMSs, APIs and E-Commerces for small local clients.

PHP, Symfony, Doctrine, Postgres, MySQL, Git, Linux, Apache Server.

**Trainee Backend Developer** at Conrad Caine from July 2013 to June 2014 in Pelotas, Brazil

Support for internal APIs and CMSs.

PHP, Symfony, CakePHP, Silex, Doctrine, MySQL, Git, SVN, Linux, Vagrant.

### Education

Computer Science at **Universidade Federal de Pelotas** (undergraduate).

2012 to 2015. Pelotas, Brazil

Informatics Technician Course at SETREM.

2009 to 2011.Três de Maio, Brazil

# Languages

Brazilian Portuguese Native

English Intermediate

Spanish Basic